#### Flavio Jose Fernandes Pires

Location: Wakefield, UK

Email: flavio.pires.1999@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/flavio-j-f-pires/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/flavio-j-f-pires/</a>

## **Professional Profile**

A dedicated, personable, and collaborative graduate student of Computer Science, searching to develop experience in the field of a service desk/software support role. I am also extremely interested in web development, and intend to build up experience on this subject through diverse pathways. Prepared to apply my upstanding intercommunicative skills and strong analytical abilities in future employment. Enthusiastic towards working both autonomously and collaboratively within a team. An opportunity of expanding my experience will be extremely rewarding, as I am confident and prepared to use the skills I have acquired throughout my recent academic achievements – as well as motivated to enhance my professional abilities throughout these initial years of IT experience.

## Personal Skills

- Outgoing, responsible, and ambitious, as shown in my recent academic achievements and hardworking history.
- Experienced in working with diverse individuals of several age groups, resulting from collaborative work alongside people from varied backgrounds.
- Fluent speaking abilities in both the English and Portuguese languages.
- Professional at adapting forms of communication depending on the social environment.
- Supportive, personable, and enthusiastic when working with a team.
- Experienced in assisting individuals confronting issues with IT devices, both personally and remotely through the use of support systems.
- Committed and diligent when working autonomously, as demonstrated through my strong academic record.

## **Technical Skills**

- Programming Languages: Java, PHP, CSS, HTML, Python
- Frameworks: Next.js, Laravel
- Database Management: phpMyAdmin
- Tools: Git, GitHub, Visual Studio Code

#### IT Support:

- Hardware and software troubleshooting
- Software installations and new hire setups
- Remote support (TeamViewer, phone assistance)
- On-site support for complex issues

## **Education**

**BSc Hons Computer Science** 

Leeds Beckett University | Sep 2021 - June 2024

Some specific details about the completion of this course included:

- Numerous modules on software engineering, web development, and networks, providing a broad understanding of the key areas in Computer Science.
- Final project focused on web development, where I built a website using two distinct frameworks, Next.js and Laravel, to compare their performance and functionality.
- Developed a strong foundation in front-end and back-end web technologies, gaining hands-on experience in modern frameworks and tools.
- Achieved First Class grades in two Web Development modules.

#### Secondary Education Diploma

Professional Computer Systems Technician Programme

Externato Dom Fuas Roupinho – Nazaré, Portugal | Sept 2017 - June 2020

## Key Focus Areas (Main IT-Related Subjects):

- Computer Architecture & Networks: Installation and configuration of local networks, peripheral devices, and internal computer architecture.
- Operating Systems & Software Applications: Installation, configuration, and management of operating systems and database systems. Experience with Microsoft Excel and information systems analysis.
- Programming: Developed proficiency in C/C++ and Java, focusing on core programming concepts such as loops, functions, data structures, and object-oriented programming.

# Primary Education Diploma

Concluded Elementary at Externato Dom Fuas Roupinho – Nazaré, Portugal | Sept 2014 – June 2017

Initiated Elementary Education at Escola Basica de 2° e 3° Ciclo Amadeu Gaudencio – Nazaré, Portugal | Sept 2009 – June 2014

# Internship

# Dayton Progress | Apr 2019 – July 2019

This internship was of 300 hours in duration, and allowed me to take part in a small team who was responsible for the resolution of IT issues within the workplace and the development of the software used inside the company.

## **Key Responsibilities:**

- · Repairing or resolving technical issues in the IT equipment;
- Preparing new equipment for employees to use it their daily duties, such as installing specific software's and creating backups in the designated devices;
- Creating an inventory of all of the IT equipment in the company, for organized tracking.

# Work Experience

## Multi Parcel Delivery

Amazon (Employed by Lightening Logistics) | Sep 2023 - Jan 2024

Key Responsibilities:

- Provide polite and professional service to customers and communicate effectively with dispatchers and team members.
- Being efficient, versatile and adaptive, as autonomous work often involves unexpected circumstances where one must demonstrate appropriate problem-solving abilities.
- Operate delivery vehicles safely and responsibly.
- Load packages into the delivery vehicle in an organized manner to ensure efficient delivery.
- Ensure packages are delivered accurately, by using the correct route and being mindful of time.

## **Warehouse Operative**

Next Distributions | Mar 2022 - Sep 2023

Responsible for picking and packing items of online orders.

#### Key Responsibilities:

- Ensuring clean, good quality items are collected and packaged for customers.
- Competent team work alongside other team colleagues and team managers.
- Being responsible and efficient regarding the safety regulations of the firm.

## **Warehouse Operative**

Stafforce Recruitment (Next Distributions) | Nov 2020 - Feb 2021

Responsible for packing items of online orders.

## Key Responsibilities:

- Ensuring clean, good quality items are collected and packaged for customers.
- Competent team work alongside other team colleagues and team managers.
- Being responsible and efficient regarding the safety regulations of the firm.

# **Factory Operative**

Medida Unica (Portugal) | Mar 2020 - July 2020

Responsible for the production of sanitary alcohol in a small company.

#### Key Responsibilities:

- Ensuring to load and unload trucks safely, using a counterbalance. (Diesel and EV).
- Being responsible for the inventory including all the orders in and out.
- Responsible for the production of gel alcohol, that was distributed all over Portugal during the Covid-19 pandemic.
- Maintaining a clean and safe work environment.